<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="dessertcontents">
        <item>INGREDIENTS
For Sugar Syrup:
2 cups sugar
5 cups water
1 tsp milk
1/4 tsp cardamom seeds
1/2 tsp saffron
1/2 tsp cardamom powder
For Gulab Jamun Balls:
1 1/2 cups khoya, grated
1/2 tsp baking soda
1/2 cup maida
1 tsp milk
INSTRUCTIONS
Take required quantity of sugar and water in a deep pan. Stir and bring to boil on high flame for sugar to dissolve.Homemade Gulab Jamun
2.Now add milk and cardamom seeds to the sugar water. Boil further and strain.Homemade Gulab Jamun
3.Then add saffron and cardamom powder and bring the mixture to rolling boil for about 5-6 minutes until it becomes little sticky.Homemade Gulab Jamun
Prepare Gulab Jamun Balls:
1.Take the grated Khoya in a medium size deep bowl.Homemade Gulab Jamun
2.Add baking soda and maida. Combine them thoroughly but gently using a spoon.Homemade Gulab Jamun
3.Add a teaspoon of milk to it and knead all of them together to make a smooth and soft dough. Add another teaspoon of milk if required.Homemade Gulab Jamun
4.Make sure that the dough is a bit softer to avoid cracking of ball while deep frying.
5.Divide the dough into equal parts and make smooth surfaced balls out of it.Homemade Gulab Jamun
6.Now heat ghee in a pan over medium flame and add the Jamun balls to deep-fry them. Cook evenly until it becomes golden brown.Homemade Gulab Jamun
7.Make sure that you do not cook on high flame otherwise the balls will burn.
8.Now drain and let them cool for few minutes.
9.Then immerse the gulab jamuns in the warm sugar syrup for at least 30 minutes. It increases in size when it soaks the sugar syrup.Homemade Gulab Jamun
10.Hot and tasty sweet dish is ready to serve.</item>
        <item>INGREDIENTS
3 c. plain 2-percent reduced fat Greek-style yogurt
2 c. half-and-half
2/3 c. sugar
1/3 c. light corn syrup
1 1/2 tsp. vanilla extract
1/4 tsp. kosher salt
3/4 c. mango jam
3/4 c. chopped fresh mango
1 tbsp. lime zest
INSTRUCTIONS
Whisk together yogurt, half-and-half, sugar, corn syrup, vanilla and salt; let stand 5 minutes. Whisk until sugar dissolves. Chill 2 hours or until very cold.
Process mango jam and chopped fresh mango in a food processor until almost smooth. Stir mango mixture and lime zest into prepared yogurt.
Pour mixture into bowl of an electric ice-cream maker, and process according to manufacturers instructions. Freeze 1 hour before serving. Store up to 1 week.</item>
        <item>INGREDIENTS
for kulfi:
2 litre milk
¼ tsp saffron / kesar
½ cup sugar
½ tsp cardamom powder
2 tbsp cashew (chopped)
2 tbsp almonds (chopped)
2 tbsp pistachios (chopped)
for instant mawa:
1 cup cream
½ cup milk
1 cup milk powder (unsweetened)
INSTRUCTIONS
firstly, in a large kadai heat 2-litre milk, ¼ tsp saffron.
stir and get the milk to a boil, without burning.
continue to cook on low flame until the milk thickens.
now simmer for 15 minutes or until the milk reduces to a quarter.
after the milk thickens add prepared mawa and mix well.
also, add ½ cup sugar and cook for 2 minutes on low flame.
now add ½ tsp cardamom powder, 2 tbsp cashew, 2 tbsp almonds and 2 tbsp pistachios.
mix well and the kulfi mixture is ready to set.
pour the kulfi mixture into kulfi moulds. if you do not have moulds, you can pour until matka or glass cups.
cover and freeze for 8 hours or until sets completely.
after 8 hours, the kulfi has set completely and is ready to serve.
finally, garnish the malai kulfi with few chopped pistachios and enjoy.</item>
        <item>INGREDIANTS
100g classic 74% dark chocolate, chopped, plus extra shards to decorate (optional)
25g butter, cubed
3 large eggs, separated
2 tbsp caster sugar
2 tbsp whipping cream (optional)
INSTRUCTIONS
Creamy chocolate mousse is an absolute classic, and this indulgent gluten-free dessert recipe is so easy to follow. Whip up the mousse with rich dark chocolate and allow to set overnight, before serving with whipped cream and chocolate shards, if you like. Stunning dinner party desserts dont get better than this!
Put the chocolate, butter and 75ml warm water (see tip, below) in a heatproof bowl set over a pan of barely simmering water. Push the chocolate and butter gently into the warm water with a wooden spoon to help it melt, but avoid stirring too much. Once three-quarters of the butter and chocolate is melted, remove the bowl from the heat. Stir until melted, smooth and glossy. Set aside until lukewarm.
Working quickly, use a spatula to stir the egg yolks into the chocolate mixture, one at a time. In a separate bowl, use an electric whisk to whip the egg whites to soft peaks, then gradually add the sugar, whisking, until stiff peaks form.
Gently fold about a fifth of the egg whites into the chocolate mixture, then fold in the rest, being careful not to knock out the air bubbles. Pour into wine or dessert glasses, cover with clingfilm and chill overnight to set.
When ready to serve, whip the cream (if using) to soft peaks. Top each glass with a spoonful of cream and decorate with chocolate shards, if you like.
Tip: For the ideal warm water temperature, mix one-third boiling water with two-thirds cold water.</item>
        <item>
INGREDIENTS
18 (9-ounce) coconut crisp cookies (we suggest Tates brand)
4 tbsp.  (1/2 stick) unsalted butter, melted
8 oz. cream cheese, at room temperature
1 (5.4-ounce) can unsweetened coconut cream
3/4 c. confectioners sugar, plus more for dusting
1 1/2 c. cold heavy cream
2 tsp. lime zest, plus 3 tablespoons lime juice, divided
2 c. blackberries
1 tbsp. granulated sugar
INSTRUCTIONS
Preheat oven to 350°F. Pulse cookies in a food processor until fine crumbs form, 12 to 15 minutes. Add butter and pulse until mixture holds together when squeezed, 10 to 12 times. Press mixture on bottom and up sides of an 11-by-8-inch removable-bottom tart pan. Bake until golden brown, 10 to 12 minutes. Cool completely.
Beat cream cheese, coconut cream, and confectioners sugar with an electric mixer on medium-high speed until smooth, 1 to 2 minutes. Reduce mixer speed to low and gradually add heavy cream. Increase speed to medium-high; beat until stiff peaks form, 2 to 4 minutes. Add 2 tablespoons lime juice and beat to return to stiff peaks, 30 seconds to 1 minute. Spoon into crust and spread to edges. Refrigerate until set, overnight or up to 2 days.
Toss blackberries with granulated sugar and remaining 1 tablespoon lime juice. Let sit, tossing occasionally, 4 to 6 minutes; spoon on top of tart. Serve topped with zest and confectioners sugar.</item>
        <item>INGREDIENTS
½ cup butter
1 cup white sugar
2 eggs
1 teaspoon vanilla extract
⅓ cup unsweetened cocoa powder
½ cup all-purpose flour
¼ teaspoon salt
¼ teaspoon baking powder
Frosting:
3 tablespoons butter, softened
3 tablespoons unsweetened cocoa powder
1 tablespoon honey
1 teaspoon vanilla extract
1 cup confectioners sugar

INSTRUCTIONS
Step 1
Preheat oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). Grease and flour an 8-inch square pan.
Step 2
In a large saucepan, melt 1/2 cup butter. Remove from heat, and stir in sugar, eggs, and 1 teaspoon vanilla. Beat in 1/3 cup cocoa, 1/2 cup flour, salt, and baking powder. Spread batter into prepared pan.
Step 3
Bake in preheated oven for 25 to 30 minutes. Do not overcook.
Step 4
To Make Frosting: Combine 3 tablespoons softened butter, 3 tablespoons cocoa, honey, 1 teaspoon vanilla extract, and 1 cup confectioners sugar. Stir until smooth. Frost brownies while they are still warm.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>