<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="nonvegcontents">
        <item>INGREDIANTS

For Seasoning the chicken
6 Chicken Wings
1 tbsp Soy Sauce
1 tbsp Ginger Garlic paste
1 tsp Chili Powder
1/4 tsp Pepper powder
Juice of half lemon
Salt to taste
For Batter
1/4 cup All purpose flour Maida
1/4 cup Corn flour
1 Egg
1 tbsp Kashmiri Chilly powder
Salt
Water

INSTRUCTIONS

Transform the chicken wings into chicken lollipop
Marinate the lollipop with soy sauce, Ginger garlic paste, chilly powder, pepper, salt and lemon juice and keep it aside for 30 minutes
To make batter by combining maida, corn flour, chilly powder, salt and water
Dip the lollipop into the batter and fry until crisp on the outside and fully cooked inside.
Once the curry comes to a boil add the kofta balls and cook
Our Chicken Lollipops are ready to be served with sauces of your choice.</item>
        <item>
            INGREDIANTS

200 gms boneless chicken
salt - to taste
½ tsp red chilli powder
¼ tsp turmeric powder
½ tsp ginger garlic paste
¼ tsp garam masala powder
¼ tsp kali mirch powder (black pepper powder)
1 tbsp corn flour
1 tbsp yogurt
½ tsp red food color
1 egg both white and the yolk
1 tbsp lemon extract
other ingredients
oil for deep frying (any edible oil)
For garnishing
onion rings
freshly chopped coriander leaves
lemon wedges

INSTRUCTIONS

Step 1 (Washing)
Firstly, wash the boneless chicken pieces well and strain the chicken until there is no water left in the chicken.
Step 2 (Marinating)
Take a mixing bowl, add the boneless chicken pieces, add salt to taste, red chilli powder, turmeric powder, ginger garlic paste, garam masala powder, kali mirch powder, corn flour and give a mix.
Add beaten yogurt, red food color, 1 egg, mix everything well, add lemon extracted juice, mix well.
Mix everything well with a spatula or with clean hands.
Cover and marinate the chicken in refrigerator for at least an hour
Step 3 (Deep frying)
Take a wok, add enough oil for deep frying.
Drop the marinated chicken pieces carefully into the oil one by one and fry them in batches.
Deep fry them on medium to low flame by stirring the pieces in between.
Deep fry for about 10-12 minutes until the chicken gets soft and tender.
Take the chicken pieces out and place them on an absorbent paper.
Continue frying the rest of the marinated chicken in second batch and take them out.
Garnish the chicken pieces with onion rings, lemon wedges and fresh coriander leaves.
Serve hot with dips.
        </item>
        <item>
INGREDIANTS

Fish - 3 medium size cleaned and slit
Coconut Oil - 3 to 5 tblspn
Curry leaves a handful
For Marination
Chilli Powder - 1 tblspn
Kashmiri Chilli Powder - 2 tblspn
Ginger Garlic Paste - 1 tblspn
Garam Masala Powder - 2 tsp
Turmeric Powder  Manjal Podi - 1 tsp
Salt to taste
Lemon Juice - 1 to 2 tblspn
Water few spoons


INSTRUCTIONS

Mix all the ingredient for the marination to a thick paste. Apply it all over the fish and leave to marinate for 30 mins, you can place it over sunlight or leave it on the counter.
Heat coconut oil in a pan, place fish over it and cook covered for 7 to 8 mins, flip over and cook on other side till crispy and cooked.
Add in curry leaves and mix well.
Serve hot.

        </item>
        <item>
INGREDIANTS

1/2 kg Mutton boneless, 20 bite size pieces
1 teaspoon Ginger garlic paste
1 pinch Turmeric powder
1 teaspoon Salt kosher  crystal salt
2 cups Water
Ingredients to make the fry
1/4 teaspoon Turmeric powder
1 teaspoon Red Chilli Powder
1/2 teaspoon Coriander powder
1/2 teaspoon Black pepper powder
1/4 teaspoon Garam masala powder
10 leaves Curry leaves
1 teaspoon Ghee
2 teaspoons Oil
1/4 teaspoon Salt or to taste

INSTRUCTIONS

Take a pressure cooker pan and pressure cook the raw mutton (tiny pieces pls)  with turmeric, salt, ginger garlic paste and water. Pressure cook for upto 4 to 5 whistles . Switch off.
The mutton will have some stock from cooking procedure you can use the stock to make soup or gravy and use the cooked meat of this recipe
Heat the cooked meat along with some stock in a pan or kadai.  Add in turmeric powder.
Adding 1/4 teaspoon salt (meat is already cooked with 1 teaspoon salt and this one is for the masala powders)
Now add in red chilli powder, coriander powder, black pepper powder. (preferably freshly ground) and garam masala powder.
Saute this until the meat gets coated with the masala all the masala powder will drink up whatever mutton juice left and start becoming dry. Throw in a few curry leaves and slow roast for 10 minutes.
Add in ghee at this stage and slow roast for another 10 minutes.
This will be roasting for next 1 hour over low flame and you will adding little oil and tossing and stir frying now and then
At one point the mutton will look extremely dry with the masala literally turning dark brown and the texture of the meat will look kind of crispy on the outer edges… that dry mutton will actually make chick chick when you saute them in the pan, that’s how it got its name in our house  that sound will prompt us that this dish is made
Finally finish off with some curry leaves.
        </item>
        <item>
INGREDIANTS

1/4 pound (1 stick) unsalted butter
1 lemon, zested and juiced
1 teaspoon chopped fresh thyme leaves
1 fresh turkey (10 to 12 pounds)
Kosher salt
Freshly ground black pepper
1 large bunch fresh thyme
1 whole lemon, halved
1 Spanish onion, quartered
1 head garlic, halved crosswise

INSTRUCTIONS

Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F.
Melt the butter in a small saucepan. Add the zest and juice of the lemon and 1 teaspoon of thyme leaves to the butter mixture. Set aside.
Take the giblets out of the turkey and wash the turkey inside and out. Remove any excess fat and leftover pinfeathers and pat the outside dry. Place the turkey in a large roasting pan. Liberally salt and pepper the inside of the turkey cavity. Stuff the cavity with the bunch of thyme, halved lemon, quartered onion, and the garlic. Brush the outside of the turkey with the butter mixture and sprinkle with salt and pepper. Tie the legs together with string and tuck the wing tips under the body of the turkey.
Roast the turkey about 2 1/2 hours, or until the juices run clear when you cut between the leg and the thigh. Remove the turkey to a cutting board and cover with aluminum foil  let rest for 20 minutes.
        </item>
        <item>
            INGREDIANTS

250 gms chicken mince
2 Eggs (slightly beaten)
3/4 cup refined flour
1/2 tsp garlic paste
1/2 tsp ginger paste
Oil (for deep frying)
2 tbsp oil
1 tsp garlic, finely chopped
1/2 cup onions, finely chopped
1 large capsicum, finely chopped
For sauce, mix together
3 tbsp corn flour (blended)
1/2 cup water
2 tbsp vinegar
2 tsp salt
2 tsp soya sauce
1/2 cup tomato puree
2 tbsp celery, chopped
2 cups water


INSTRUCTIONS

Mix together the chicken, egg, flour, garlic and ginger paste, enough water so as to have a thick batter. Leave this for 5-10 minutes.
2.Heat the oil, keeping the heat high drop heaped teaspoonfuls of batter and fry to a golden brown. Drain on absorbent paper till required.
3.Heat 2 Tbsp of oil, and stir-fry the garlic and onion in it over high heat, till the onions look glossy. Add the capsicum and turn around a few times.
4.Add the sauce mixture, and simmer till the sauce thickens and becomes translucent.
5.Add the fried balls, turn around a few times and serve.
To make the Manchurian balls juicy and tender you can first soak the chicken pieces in lukewarm water for a while.
Key Ingredients chicken mince, Eggs (slightly beaten), refined flour, garlic paste, ginger paste, Oil (for deep frying), oil, garlic, onions, capsicum, corn flour (blended), water, vinegar, salt, soya sauce, tomato puree, celery, water

        </item>
    </string-array>
</resources>