<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="northcontents">
        <item>1 cup Maida
1 cup Ata
1 Tbsp ghee
1 Tbsp yogurt
1/2 tsp baking soda
1/2 tsp Ajwain
as per taste Salt
as required Water to knead the dough

(1) For Yogurt Gravy
1 cup yogurt
1 Tbsp Kashmiri red chilli powder
1/2 tsp coriander powder
1/2 tsp turmeric powder
2 butter cubes
as per taste Salt

(2) For Paneer soaking
1 cup lukewarm water
200 gms cubed paneer
as per taste Salt

(3) For Onion Tomato Masala
1 medium size onion chopped
1 medium size tomato chopped
1 Tbsp red chilli powder
as per taste Salt
2 Tbsp butter

(4) For Gravy
3 Tbsp ghee
1 Tbsp butter
1 bay leaf
2-3 cloves
3-4 green cardamom
2-3 whole red chillies

Yogurt gravy
1-2 green chillies halved
3 large tomatoes chopped
6 cashew nuts
1 inch ginger chopped
2-3 garlic cloves crushed
1 Tbsp Kashmiri red chilli powder
2 drops kewra water
1.2 cups water
as per taste Salt
            For Tandoori Roti  in a bowl add Maida, Ata, ghee, baking soda, sugar, salt, ajwain and mix well.
Add water as required and make a dough to make the Roti. Keep it covered with a wet muslin cloth for 1 hour. Smear a little oil on the dough
Roll out the Rotis. Smear water well one side. Keep a Tawa Pre heated.Place the watered side on the tawa face down and bubbles will be seen after 2 mins. Flip the tawa and roast the reverse side. Set aside once done and complete the batch.

For Paneer Butter Masala -  soak the cubed paneer in lukewarm water and set aside. This is to make the paneer soft.
 Yogurt gravy  in a bowl add Kashmiri red chilli powder, coriander powder, turmeric powder, yogurt, salt and butter. Whisk well and set aside foer later useGravy - in a wok heat ghee and butter. Add bay leaf, cloves, green cardamom, chopped ginger, green chillies, whole red chilies, crushed garlic, sliced onion. Stir until onions are softened. Add prepared yogurt gravy and stir until ghee surfaces on top Add Kashmiri red chilli powder, chopped tomatoes, cashews, salt, water and cook covered for 10 mins until tomatoes are mushy. Set aside to cool for 2 3 mins. Discard the bay leaf. Take a hand blender and blend until smooth and texture is shiny of the gravy Onion Tomato Masala  in a wok heat butter and add chopped onions, chopped tomatoes. Stir well.Add the gravy. Add the paneer cubes and cook on low flame for 3 4 mins. The gravy will thicken a little due to cashew nuts. Add water if desired. Set aside and add dry kasuri methi crushed To plate add coriander leaves, a little whisked yogurt to give the cream effect but dont add fresh cream. Serve hot with Tandoori Roti and enjoy a complete meal.</item>
        <item>INGREDIENTS

4 Large potatoes, boiled
250 gms paneer (cottage cheese)
50 gms maida
1 tbsp Coriander Leaves, chopped
3 Onions
1 tbsp ginger garlic paste
2 Tomatoes
200 ml malai or cream
2 tbsp raisins and cashew nuts
50 gms cashew nuts paste
1/2 tsp haldi (turmeric)
1/2 tsp red chilli powder
1/2 tsp kitchen king masala
1 tbsp Kasturi methi (dry Fenugreek)
to taste salt
1 tbsp sugar

INSTRUCTIONS

Refrigerate the boiled potatoes for 4 to 6 hours as this makes it easy to cook koftas.
Mash the boiled potatoes, paneer, maida. The mix should not be too hard or too soft. Add salt, chopped coriander leaves and mix well.
Cut the raisins and cashew nuts into very small pieces and add 1/2 tsp of sugar to the mix.
Heat up the oil for deep frying.
Roll out the balls from the dough you prepared and stuff the dry fruit mix in the centre.
Fry the koftas and if they break in hot oil then dust them with dry maida before putting them in.

Prepare the gravy

Fry some onion, ginger garlic paste and tomato paste.
Mix the cashew nut paste with 2 Tbsp of warm milk and pour it into the paste.
Except kasturi methi, add all the dry masala into the paste and saute till the oil separates itself.
Add and a half cup of water and simmer the gravy till its done.
Add cream or malai, 1 Tbsp of sugar and kasturi methi.
Simmer the gravy till the oil starts separating and once its done, put the fried koftas into the gravy and serve hot with chapatis.
</item>
        <item>Ingredients for Vegetable Biryani Recipe

Basmati Rice 1 1/2 cups
Carrots 2 medium
Carrots 1/2 inch pieces 2 medium
French beans 1/2 inch pieces 15
Cauliflower 10-12 florets
Green peas shelled 1 cup
Salt to taste
Green cardamons 8
Black cardamom 1
Cloves 15
Cinnamon 1/2 inch stick
Bay leaf 1
Caraway seeds (shahi jeera) 1/2 teaspoon
Ginger garlic paste 1 1/2 tablespoons
Turmeric powder 1 teaspoon
Red chilli powder 1 tablespoon
Coriander powder 1 tablespoon
Yogurt 1/2 cup
Rose water 1/2 teaspoon
Saffron (kesar) a few strands
Fresh tomato puree 1 cup
Garam masala powder 1 teaspoon
Fresh coriander leaves chopped 2 tablespoons
Fresh mint leaves chopped 2 tablespoons

Method
            Step 1
Boil rice in four cups of salted boiling water with two green cardamoms, one black cardamom, five cloves, half inch stick of cinnamon, until three fourth done. Drain excess water and set aside. Heat a non stick pan. Add the remaining green cardamoms, cloves, black cardamom and cinnamon along with bay leaf and caraway seeds and roast. Add onions, carrot, French beans, cauliflower florets and green peas.
Step 2
Sprinkle salt, cover and cook on medium heat for two minutes. Add ginger garlic paste mixed with a little water and stir. Cover and cook for two minutes. Add turmeric powder, red chilli powder and coriander powder and cook.Whisk yogurt with rose water and saffron. Add a little water or milk and whisk well. Add tomato puree to the vegetables along with half teaspoon garam masala powder and mix well. Simmer for two minutes. Take a microwave safe deep bowl.
Step 3
Arrange a layer of rice at the bottom. Over that arrange half the cooked vegetables followed by another layer of rice. Sprinkle half of the remaining garam masala powder, half the coriander leaves, half the mint leaves and half the yogurt mixture. Arrange the remaining vegetables followed by the remaining rice.Sprinkle the remaining garam masala powder, remaining coriander leaves, remaining mint leaves and the remaining yogurt mixture. Cover with a silicon lid and cook in the microwave oven for four to five minutes on HIGH . Let it stand for five minutes. Serve hot.</item>
        <item>3 cup maida or plain flour
▢1 tsp salt
▢water for kneading
▢oil for greasing
for stuffing:
▢6 tsp oil
▢6 clove garlic (finely chopped)
▢2 inch ginger (finely chopped)
▢4 chilli (finely chopped)
▢8 tbsp spring onion
▢2 cup carrot (grated)
▢4 cup cabbage (shredded)
▢1 tsp pepper (crushed)
▢1 tsp salt


INSTRUCTIONS

firstly, prepare stuffing by heating 3 tsp oil and saute 3 clove garlic, 1 inch ginger and 2 chilli.
also, add 2 tbsp spring onion and saute on high flame.
further, add 1 cup carrot and 2 cup cabbage. stir fry on high flame.
now add ½ tsp pepper and ½ tsp salt.
additionally, 2 tbsp spring onion and stuffing mixture is ready.
further, pinch a small ball sized momos dough and flatten.
now dust with some maida and start to roll using a rolling pin.
roll to almost medium thin circle. around 4  5 inch in diameter. make sure you roll from sides and keep the centre slightly thick.
now place a heaped tbsp of prepared stuffing in the centre.
start pleating the edges slowly and gather everything.
press in middle and seal the momos forming a bundle.
heat a steamer and arrange the momos in the tray without touching each other.
furthermore, steam momos for 10 12 minutes or till shiny sheen appears over it.
finally, veg momos recipe is ready to enjoy with momos chutney.</item>
        <item>Ingrediants
1 Kg carrot
1 1/2 litre milk
8 Green cardamoms
5-7 tbsp ghee
5-7 tbsp sugar
2 tbsp raisins
1 tbsp almonds, shredded
2 tbsp dates, chopped


1 Kg carrot
1 1/2 litre milk
8 Green cardamoms
5-7 tbsp ghee
5-7 tbsp sugar
2 tbsp raisins
1 tbsp almonds, shredded
2 tbsp dates, chopped
        Instructions
Wash the carrot and peel them.
Grate the carrot to medium thickness.
Add the carrots and milk in a heavy bottom pan and cook on low heat until all the milk is absorbed.
Add ghee in the pan along with cardamom powder.
Fry for 4 5 minutes on low heat.
Keep stirring continuously.
Add sugar and cook for another 4 5 minutes.
Add grated khoya and cook for 15 20 minutes on low heat until ghee starts to leave on the sides.
Keep stirring in between.
Garnish with almond and pistachio slivers.
Serve warm.</item>
        <item>Ingredients Of Aloo Paratha
250 gm whole wheat flour
Pinch of salt
1 cup water
50 ml oil
For the filling
500 gm potatoes
20 gm coriander leaves
20 gm ginger garlic paste
75 gm onions
5 gm green chillies
5 gm turmeric
5 gm chilli powder
10 ml lime juice
Oil for frying


How to Make Aloo Paratha
1. Make a soft dough with the specified ingredients.
2. Divide the dough into balls, as per the required size.
3. Chop the onions, green chillies and the coriander leaves. Then boil the potatoes  remove the skin and mash.
4. Add the rest of the ingredients and mix well. Take each portion of the dough, flatten it on palm.
5. Stuff the filling in the dough and roll into balls. With a rolling pin, flatten the balls into 1 2  thick round parathas.
6. Grease a pan with a little oil and heat on a medium flame.
7. Cook the parathas until both sides are golden and cooked through.</item>



    </string-array>
</resources>