<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="southcontents">
        <item>INGREDIANTS
Dosa batter  1 cup
Onions  1/2 cup (chopped)
Tomatoes  1/2 cup (chopped)
Green Chili  1 (chopped)
Salt to taste
Chaat masala  1/2 tsp
INSTRUCTIONS
Heat a non stick pan.
When the pan is hot, pour a ladle full of batter on it and spread to make a small circle.
Sprinkle some onions, tomatoes and green chili on top.
Press with the back of a ladle.
Pour oil on the sides and on top.
Fry till brown and crispy.
Flip and cook from other side as well.
Sprinkle salt and chaat masala on top.
Serve hot.</item>
        <item>INGREDIENTS
2 tbsp oil
1 tsp mustard
1 tsp urad dal
pinch of hing or asafoetida
1 tsp chana dal
few curry leaves
3 tbsp peanuts or groundnut (roasted)
1 cup raw mango (grated)
2 green chilli (slit)
¼ tsp turmeric or haldi
2 cup cooked rice
salt to taste
2 tbsp coconut (grated)
2 tbsp coriander leaves (finely chopped)
INSTRUCTIONS
firstly, in a large kadai heat oil.
add in 1 tsp mustard, 1 tsp urad dal and 1 tsp chana dal, pinch of hing and few curry leaves.
allow to splutter.
furthermore add in 3 tbsp roasted peanuts and saute for a minute.
also add in 1 cup raw mango, 2 green chilli and ¼ tsp turmeric.
saute for a minute or till mango shrinks.
now add in 2 cup cooked rice and salt to taste.
mix gently without breaking rice grains.
cover and simmer for 2 minutes or till rice absorbs flavours.
furthermore add in 2 tbsp coconut and 2 tbsp coriander leaves. mix well.
finally, serve mango rice or mavinakayi chitranna hot or to lunch box.
        </item>
        <item>INGREDIENTS
for pressure cooking
1 tsp ghee or  clarified butter
½ cup rice (rinsed)
½ cup moong dal (rinsed)
4 cup water
½ tsp salt

for tempering

2 tbsp ghee or clarified butter
1 tsp cumin or jeera
½ tsp pepper (crushed)
1 inch ginger (finely chopped)
2 chilli (slit)
10 cashew or kaju (halves)
pinch hing or asafoetida
INSTRUCTIONS
firstly, in a pressure cooker heat 1 tsp ghee.
add ½ cup rice, ½ cup moong dal and saute for a minute or until it turns aromatic.
further, add 4 cup water and ½ tsp salt. mix well.
cover and pressure cook for 5 whistles on medium flame.
once the pressure settles down, open the cooker and give a good mix.
furthermore, in a pan heat 2 tbsp ghee.
also add 1 tsp cumin, ½ tsp pepper, 1 inch ginger, 2 chilli, 10 cashew and pinch hing.
saute on low flame until cashew turns golden brown.
pour the tempering over cooked rice and dal mixture.
give a good mix, add more ghee if required.
finally, serve ven pongal or khara pongal with coconut chutney and sambar.</item>
        <item>INGREDIANTS
12 Dry Red Chillies , (keep aside half of them for seasoning)
3 tablespoons Whole Black Peppercorns
6 tablespoons Cumin seeds (Jeera)
1/2 cup Chana dal (Bengal Gram Dal)
1/4 cup White Urad Dal (Split)
1/2 cup Sesame seeds (Til seeds)
1 cup Dry coconut (kopra) , grated
1 teaspoon Mustard seeds (Rai or Kadugu)
20 Curry leaves
1/2 teaspoon Asafoetida (hing)
1/2 cup Jaggery
1/4 cup Tamarind Paste , (Or Soaked tamarind pulp 1 2 cup)
1/2 cup Roasted Peanuts (Moongphali)
1-1/2 cups Oil
INSTRUCTIONS
In a kadai, dry roast each of the ingredients individually one at a time, on a low heat  Urad Dal, Chana Dal  both until slightly brown, black pepper, Cumin seeds, Red Chillies a bit until fragrant.
Allow to cool by spreading them on a large plate. Once cooled, grind all the above dry roasted ingredients by using a mixer grinder. Set aside.
Next dry roast these ingredients  Sesame seeds, Dry coconut. Coarsely grind both of these ingredients and mix it with the ground spices you prepared in mixer earlier.
In an aluminium vessel, or a thick bottomed Kadai, heat about 2 cups of water, add jaggery, tamarind pulp, salt to taste and bring to a boil. Check on the tangy  sweet admixture of flavours. Adjust as per requirement by adding in more jaggery or tamarind pulp as this is the mixture that gives the rice its unique flavour.
Allow to cool. Once the jaggery  tamarind mixture cools down add the ground dal spice and coconut powder and stir well to form a nice thick semi dry dough like consistency. Set aside.
In a kadai or wok, heat oil, add in the mustard seeds to splutter, curry leaves and dry red chillies.
Add the groundnuts and fry for about 2 3 minutes on a low flame.
To the above mixture, finally, add asafoetida or hing powder.
While its still hot transfer it into the kadai in which is the jaggery tamarind and spice powder mixture is resting. Stir well so that the oil and tempered spices coat the overall mixture and help in preserving it for a longer time
 Puliyogare Gojju Recipe is ready, you can store this in an air tight container in a refrigerator for weeks together.
Just take a few table spoons of the gojju and mix it with cooked plain rice, as and when you want to relish this tangy goodness.
Puliyogare Gojju Recipe with Aama Vadai, or Akki Peni Sandige for breakfast or lunch.</item>
        <item>INGREDIENTS
1 cup bombay rava or semolina or sooji
2 tbsp oil
1 tsp mustard or rai or sasuve
½ tsp chana dal (optional)
½ tsp urad dal
1 dried red chilli
few curry leaves
½ onion (finely chopped)
2 green chilli (finely chopped)
1 inch ginger (finely chopped)
3 cups water
½ tsp sugar
½ tsp salt
1 tsp ghee or clarified butter
½ lemon juice
2 tbsp coriander (finely chopped)
INSTRUCTIONS
firstly, dry roast 1 cup bombay rava on low flame for 2 3 minutes. keep aside to cool completely.
now in a large kadai heat 2 tbsp oil and add 1 tsp mustard, ½ tsp urad dal, 1 dried red chilli and few curry leaves. also add jeera for more flavour.
now saute till the mustard seeds splutter.
add in ½ onion and saute well.
also saute 2 green chilli and 1 inch ginger.
now pour 3 cups water and get to vigorous boil.
further add ½ tsp sugar, ½ tsp salt and 1 tsp ghee. mix well.
keeping the flame on low start adding roasted rava slowly, stirring continuously in another hand.
this helps to prevent from any lumps formation.
now mix continuously till the rava absorbs water.
cover and simmer on low flame for 5 minutes or till upma is cooked well.
furthermore add ½ lemon juice and 2 tbsp coriander leaves. mix well.
finally, serve rava upma or uppittu with coconut chutney or plain.</item>
        <item>INGREDIANTS
Urad dal  2 cups
Ginger  1 inch piece ( chopped )
Fresh coconut  1 inch piece ( cut into thin slices )
Green chili  1 ( chopped )
Salt to taste
Oil for frying
How to make Vada

Preparation time 20 minutes

Cooking time 30 minutes
INSTRUCTIONS
Wash and soak urd dal in water for 1 to 2 hours.
Drain the water and grind the dal till smooth.
Add green chili, coconut, ginger and salt.
Heat oil in a frying pan.
Apply little water in your palm and keep a lemon size dough in it.
Gently make a hole in the center.
Drop the vada in the oil and deep fry till golden brown from both the sides.
Serve hot with sambhar.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>